Guide to the Kim Fielding Photographs MSS.628
Fales Library and Special Collections
Kim Fielding Photographs
1972-2002
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fielding, Kim
Bugarčić, Gary Ray
MSS.628
8.25 linear feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 6 small flat boxes, and 1 oversize folder in shared housing
3 sound tape reels
1 videocassettes (vhs-c)
1 videocassettes (vhs)
Kim Fielding (d. 2014) was a Welsh artist, photographer, and curator. His photography and other artwork was provactive and confrontational, often employing bondage, covering models with subtances, or putting models in enclosed containers. Fielding also used his photography to document the arts communities he was part of, including Berlin, New York, and South America, in addition to his home in Cardiff. While living in New York City in the 1980s and 1990s, Fielding was a regular presence in the downtown arts scene, waited tables in the East Village, bartended at Cave Canem (the basement of Lucky Cheng's), and photographed the larger cultural moment he was a part of. The Kim Fielding Photographs (dated 1972-2002) consist primarily of photographic materials created by Fielding documenting the period of his life in New York City, and his engagement with the downtown arts scene in the 1980s and 1990s. Materials include photographic negatives, contact sheets, slides, and prints of candid images from gallery openings, clubs, events such as the East Village drag festival Wigstock, and other venues, such as PS 122, La Mama, The Kitchen, and Darinka: A Performance Studio. The collection also includes posed photographs taken by Fielding, some of which are pornographic. Notable figures from the downtown arts scene documented in the collection include Carlo McCormick, Joey Arias, Richard Kern, George Petros, and Ruby Ray, amongst others. The collection also includes a small amount of audio and video recordings.
Scope and Contents
The Kim Fielding Photographs (dated 1972-2002) consist primarily of photographic materials created by Fielding documenting the period of his life in New York City, and his engagement with the downtown arts scene in the 1980s and 1990s. Materials include photographic negatives, contact sheets, slides, and prints of candid images from gallery openings, clubs, events such as the East Village drag festival Wigstock, and other venues, such as PS 122, La Mama, The Kitchen, and Darinka: A Performance Studio. The collection also includes posed photographs taken by Fielding, some of which are pornographic. Notable figures from the downtown arts scene documented in the collection include Carlo McCormick, Joey Arias, Richard Kern, George Petros, and Ruby Ray, amongst others. The collection also includes a small amount of audio and video recordings.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Gary Ray Bugarčić in April 2023; the accession number with this purchase is 2023.037.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Biographical Note
Kim Fielding (d. 2014) was a Welsh artist, photographer, and curator. His photography and other artwork was provactive and confrontational, often employing bondage, covering his models with subtances, or putting his models in enclosed containers. Fielding also used his photography to document the arts communities he was part of, including Berlin, New York, and South America, in addition to his home in Cardiff. While living in New York City in the 1980s and 1990s, Fielding was a regular presence in the downtown arts scene, waited tables in the East Village, bartended at Cave Canem (the basement of Lucky Cheng's), and photographed the larger cultural moment he was a part of.
Custodial History
Fielding's photographic materials were located at Tactile Bosch in Cardiff. Fielding's friends Elizabeth Kresch and Matt Duncan retrieved the materials documenting his life in New York City and sent the collection to Gary Ray Bugarčić in 2019.
Appraisal
Optical discs were determined to be out of scope and appraised out of the collection.
Photographs.; East Village (New York, N.Y.); Alternative spaces (Arts facilities); Artists and community -- New York (State) -- New York; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Bugarčić, Gary Ray
- Photograph Negatives -- General, circa late 1980s-mid 1990s (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 3, Folder 1-5)
- Photograph Negatives and Slides -- General, circa late 1980s-mid 1990s (Box 1, Folder 2-3, Box 4, Folder 5)
- Photograph Negatives, Slides, and Contact Sheets -- General, circa late 1980s-mid 1990s (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Photograph Prints -- General, circa late 1980s-mid 1990s (Box 1, Folder 4-7, Box 4, Folder 6)
- Photograph Prints -- Eric, Charley, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lydia Lunch and Others, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- NYC Negatives, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10-11, Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Pornographic Phtographs and Descriptions, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Portfolio, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Wigstock, Edgar Olive, Karen Black Band, Thrust Band, Hilly Kristal, circa late 1980s-mid 1990s (Box 2, Folder 3-6)
- "Lightbox Scenario" Binder (NYC, Cardiff, London, Bristol), circa 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
- "NY People" Binder, 1989-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4-5, Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- NYC Binder, circa 1994 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
- "Yr Wythroios" / F.D.T., 1972 (Box 9, Quarter inch audio reel 628.0001)
- "Mozart No. 1", undated (Box 9, Quarter inch audio reel 628.0002)
- Untitled Audio Reel, undated (Box 9, Quarter inch audio reel 628.0003)
- "Entrapment" Performance, 1998 (Box 9, Vhs-c 628.0004)
- "NYC Footage/Galapagos/Siberia", 2002 (Box 9, Vhs 628.0005)
- Poster, undated (Box Shared Fales 093, Folder 13)